A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections Publications FA1395
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Publications, 1952-1970; 4
  - The Norwalk Plan of Team Teaching, Fifth Report, 1962-1963, Norwalk Board of Education (Box 71, Folder 754)
  - Manual for Area Coordinators and Area Committees, Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction (MPATI), Midwest Council on Airborne Television Instruction, 1960 October 1 (Box 71, Folder 755)
    Includes correspondence and tentative schedule for Fall 1961
  - An Exciting Profession: New Horizons for Secondary School Teachers, Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School, J. Lloyd Trump, undated (Box 71, Folder 756)
  - New Directions to Quality Education: The Secondary School Tomorrow, Appointed by The National Association of Secondary-School Principals, A Department of the National Education Association, by J. Lloyd Trump, undated (Box 71, Folder 757)
  - New Horizons in Learning, The Brevard County Project, 1960-1961 (Box 71, Folder 758)
  - Manual for Studies of Space Utilization in Colleges and Universities by John Dale Russell and James I. Doi, American Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers, 1957 (Box 71, Folder 759)
  - New Approaches in Education: A Study of Experimental Programs in Independent Schools by David Mallery, National Council of Independent Schools (NCIS), 1961 (Box 71, Folder 760)
  - More Power to Them: A Report of Faculty and Student Experience in the Encouragement of Student Initiative, C. L. Barber, 1962 (Box 71, Folder 761)
    Report submitted to the presidents of Amherst College, Mount Holyoke College, Smith College, and the University of Massachusetts by the Committee for New College
  - The Major in English, Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Arkansas Experiment in Teacher Education, 1956 June (Box 71, Folder 762)
  - Southern Project Report, 1953-1955, National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (Box 71, Folder 763)
  - Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction: A Regional Exploration in Education, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 764)
  - This is Airborne...Midwest Program on Airborne Television Initiative, undated (Box 71, Folder 765)
  - Pilot Study in the Preparation of Elementary Teachers - Final Report, University of Louisville, 1967 November (Box 71, Folder 766)
  - 10 Years of Closed Circuit TV at Stephens College, 1955-1965, Stephens College Educational Report: IV, Ralph C. Leydon, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 767)
  - A Report to the Fund for The Advancement of Education: The Teaming of Principals Project, Nicholas J. Anastasiow and Abraham S. Fischler, Palo Alto Unified School District, Fall 1966 (Box 71, Folder 768)
  - Committee for Economic Development and Economic Research in College-Community Centers, 1952 November (Box 72, Folder 769)
  - Instructional Television Research - Project Number One: An Experimental Study of College Instruction Using Broadcast Television, San Francisco State College, Robert E. Dreher and Walcott H. Beatty, 1958 April (Box 72, Folder 770)
  - Instructional Television Research - Project Number Two: An Experimental Study of College Instruction Using Broadcast Television, San Francisco State College, Albert R. Lepore and Jack D. Wilson, Fall 1958 (Box 72, Folder 771)
  - Inter-Institutional Teaching by Television in the Oregon State System of Higher Education - Report: No. 1-1957-59, Glenn Starlin and John E. Lallas, 1960 March (Box 72, Folder 772)
    A "Colleges for Oregon's Future: 1960-1970" Publication, Oregon State System of Higher Education, Eugene, Oregon
  - An Investigation of Television Teaching Conducted by The St. Louis Educational Television Commission and The St. Louis Public Schools, 1956 September (Box 72, Folder 773)
  - Survey of University Adult Education in the Metropolitan Area of New York, Caroline Ellwood, School of Continuing Education, New York University, 1967 July (Box 72, Folder 774)
  - Locus of Change: Staff Utilization Studies, Fifth Report on Staff Utilization Studies, 1962 January (Box 72, Folder 775)
    Reprinted from the January 1962 issue of The Bulletin, a publication of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals
  - An Inventory for College Graduates On: National and International Policies, Foreign Study and Travel, Community Interests, Opinions and Values: A Research Questionnaire, C. Robert Pace, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 776)
  - Integration in the Christian Liberal Arts College by the St. Olaf College Self Study Committee, 1956 (Box 72, Folder 777)
  - The Financial Situation of American Arts and Science and Science Graduate Students, Report No. 74, National Opinion Research Center, University of Chicago, 1960 April (Box 72, Folder 778, Box 73, Folder 779-781)
  - Federal Support for Adult Education: A Directory of Programs and Services, The Adult Education Association of the USA, 1966 September 7 (Box 73, Folder 782)
  - A Compendium of Team Teaching in the Dundee School, 1958-1966, Greenwich Public Schools, Greenwich, Connecticut (Box 73, Folder 783)
  - White and Negro Schools in the South: An Analysis of Biracial Education, An Objective Analysis of Biracial Education in the South, Presented by a Group of Southern Educators, Truman M. Pierce, James B. Kincheloe, R. Edgar Moore, Galen N. Drewry, and Bennie E. Carmichael, 1955 (Box 73, Folder 784)
  - The Discipline of Education, Edited by John Walton and James L. Kuethe, 1963 (Box 73, Folder 785)
  - The Journal of Educational Sociology - Special Issue, Education of Puerto Rican Children in New York City, Vol. 28, No. 4, Pages 145-192, 1954 December (Box 73, Folder 786)
  - The Efficiency of Freedom: Report of The Committee on Government and Higher Education, 1959 (Box 73, Folder 787)
  - Education in the Perspective of History, Edward D. Myers, 1960 (Box 74, Folder 788)
  - The Computer in American Education, Don D. Bushnell and Dwight W. Allen, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 789)
  - The Computer in American Education: Issues and Applications, Preliminary Papers for the Association for Educational Data Systems (AEDS)-Stanford School of Education, 1965 November 1-3 (Box 74, Folder 790)
  - College Teaching by Television: Report of a Conference Sponsored Jointly by the Committee on Television of the American Council on Education and the Pennsylvania State University at University Park, Pennsylvania, October 20-23, 1957, American Council on Education, 1958 (Box 74, Folder 791)
  - Curriculum Development Through School and University Collaboration: The Pittsburgh Curriculum Continuity Demonstration 4., A Report of the Regional Commission on Educational Coordination and the Learning Research and Development Center, J. Steele Gow, Jr., undated (Box 74, Folder 792)
  - Commissioner's 1961 Catalog of Educational Change, The University of the State of New York, The State Education Department, Albany, 1961 October (Box 74, Folder 793)
  - Exploring Improved Teaching Patterns: Second Report on Staff Utilization-Studies, Prepared for The Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School, 1959 January (Box 76, Folder 794)
    Reprinted from the January 1959 issue of The Bulletin, a publication of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals
  - Report No. 2 - Experimental Study in Instructional Procedures, Miami University, Oxford, Ohio, 1957 October 1 (Box 76, Folder 795)
  - Progress Report: Experimental Study in Instructional Procedures, Miami University, Oxford, Ohio, 1956 October 1 (Box 76, Folder 796)
  - The Emerging City and Higher Adult Education, Southern Regional Education Board, 1963 (Box 76, Folder 797)
    Papers presented at the Tulane University Institute for Deans and Directors of Adult Education, June 22-29, 1963, and at the Summer Graduate Workshop for Administrators of Higher Adult Education, University of Tennessee, July 22-August 10, 1963
  - Emergence of a Concept: A Dynamic New Educational Program for the Southwest, Edited by Charles Franklin Parker, 1965 (Box 76, Folder 798)
  - An Evaluation of Team Teaching, 1960-1964, Division of Curriculum Development and Research, Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1965 February (Box 76, Folder 799)
  - Faculty Personnel Policies in State Universities, H. K. Newburn, Montana State University, 1959 October (Box 76, Folder 800)
  - Expanding Resources for College Teaching: A Report of the Conference on College Teaching in Washington, D.C., January 19-20, 1956, American Council on Education, Edited by Charles G. Dobbins, Series I - Reports of Committees and Conferences-Number 60, Volume XX, 1956 October (Box 76, Folder 801)
  - Graduate Education: A Critique and a Program, Oliver C. Carmichael, 1961 (Box 76, Folder 802)
  - General Education in School and College: A Committee Report By Members of the Faculties of Andover, Exeter, Lawrenceville, Harvard, Princeton, and Yale (2 copies), 1952 (Box 77, Folder 803)
  - Preparing Teachers for Secondary Schools: Report of a Post-Baccalaureate Program Leading to a Master of Education Degree: Pilot Study II of an Experimental Program in Teacher Education, Conducted by Temple University, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 804)
  - Preparing Teachers for Secondary Schools: Report of a Post-Baccalaureate Program Leading to a Master of Education Degree: Pilot Study II of an Experimental Program in Teacher Education (EPTE), Conducted by Temple University - Paperback, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 805)
  - Public School Revenue Trends, 1940-1952, by Galen N. Drewry, A Series of Five Studies of Education in The South, Southern States Cooperative Program in Educational Administration - Number 2, 1954 (Box 77, Folder 806)
  - Trends in Public School Enrichment Services (Library, Vocational Education, and School Lunch), by Bennie E. Carmichael A Series of Five Studies of Education in The South, Southern States Cooperative Program in Educational Administration - Number 3, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 807)
  - Trends in School-Age Population, Enrollment, and Attendance, By Glen E. Robinson, A Series of Five Studies of Education in The South, Southern States Cooperative Program in Educational Administration - Number 4, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 808)
  - Trends in Public School Teaching Personnel (Salary, Training, and Pupil-Teacher Ratio), By Fred W. Gupton, A Series of Five Studies of Education in The South, Southern States Cooperative Program in Educational Administration - Number 5, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 809)
  - School Aides at Work: Catskill Area Project in Small School Design, 1959 (Box 79, Folder 810)
  - Rural Renaissance: Revitalizing Small High Schools, Edmund A. Ford, Bulletin 1961, No. 11, US Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Office of Education (Box 79, Folder 811)
  - The Revolution in the Schools, Ronald Gross and Judith Murphy, 1964 July (Box 79, Folder 812)
  - Schools of Tomorrow - Today: A Report on Educational Experiments Prepared for the New York State Education Department, by Arthur D. Morse, The University of the State of New York, The State Education Department, Albany, NY, 1960 (Box 79, Folder 813)
  - The San Francisco Teacher Recruitment and Training Program, A Final Report, A Five Year Cooperative Project, 1954-1959, 1960 July (Box 79, Folder 814)
  - School Readiness: Behavior Tests Used at the Gessell Institute, Frances L. Ilg & Louise Bates Ames, 1965 (Box 80, Folder 815)
  - Schools in Transition: Community Experiences in Desegregation, Edited by Robin M. Williams, Jr. and Margaret W. Ryan, 1954 (Box 80, Folder 816)
  - The Sixty College Study, A Second Look, A Comparison of Financial Operating Data for 1957-1958, With a Study of Income and Expenditures in Sixty Colleges - Year 1953-1954, 1960 (Box 80, Folder 817)
  - Seeking Improved Learning Opportunities: Fourth Report on Staff Utilization Studies, Prepared for The Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School, 1961 January (Box 80, Folder 818)
    Reprinted from the January 1961 issue of The Bulletin, a publication of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals
  - The Basic Courses at Stephens...A Revision, A Projection, Ralph C. Leydon - Stephens College Educational Report: II, 1966 January (Box 80, Folder 819)
  - Airborne Television Instruction and Better Quality Education: A Summary of Remarks and Charts Presented to Midwest Business and Education Leaders, by Philip H. Coombs, 1960 December (Box 80, Folder 820)
  - Institute for Philosophical Research, Biennial Report, 1952-1954 (Box 81, Folder 821)
  - Blueprint for Talent Searching, Richard L. Plaut, 1957 (Box 81, Folder 822)
  - Proceedings of the Conference on College and University Interinstitutional Cooperation, Princeton, New Jersey, Editor: John J. Wittich, 1962 April (Box 81, Folder 823)
  - College/High School Cooperation: Instituting the Advanced Placement Program in Pittsburgh, 1961 June 1 (Box 81, Folder 824)
  - College Admission with Advanced Standing: Final Report and Summary of the June 1955 Evaluating Conferences of the School and College Study, Published by The School and College Study of Admission with Advanced Standing, 1956 March (Box 81, Folder 825)
  - California and Western Conference Cost and Statistical Study, 1954-1955 (Box 81, Folder 826)
  - Attitudes of Educators Toward Exceptional Children: Syracuse University Special Education and Rehabilitation Monograph Series 3, Norris G. Haring, George G. Stern, and William M. Cruickshank, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 827)
  - Abridged Reports - Abridged Edition of the Report for 1954-1955 - Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, Clyde M. Hill, 1954-1960, 1956 (Box 81, Folder 828)
  - American Education Today, Edited by Paul Woodring and John Scanlon, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 829)
  - The Campus and the State, Malcolm Moos & Francis E. Rourke, 1959 (Box 82, Folder 830)
  - The Louisville Story, by Omer Carmichael and Weldon James, 1957 (Box 82, Folder 831)
  - Behind the Classroom Door, John I. Goodlad, M. Frances Klein, and Associates, 1970 (Box 82, Folder 832)
  - Closed Circuit Television: A Report of the Chelsea Project, New York City Board of Education, Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1962 (Box 82, Folder 833)
  - The Arkansas Experiment in Teacher Education: A State-Wide Program Financed by The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1953 September (Box 82, Folder 834)
  - Change and Renewal, Report of the National Education Association (NEA) Development Project, undated (Box 83, Folder 835)
  - Teacher Assistant: An Abridged Report: The Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, 1959 February (Box 83, Folder 836)
  - Teacher Preparation for Mothers Who Are College Graduates: A Report - The Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, 1959 September (Box 83, Folder 837)
  - Teaching Fellows: An Experimental Program for Recruitment and Preparation of Superior Teachers, The Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, 1960 May (Box 83, Folder 838)
  - How Much Are Students Learning?: Plans for a National Assessment of Education, A Report from The Committee on Assessing the Progress of Education, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1968 (Box 83, Folder 839)
  - American Policy and the Soviet Challenge: Foreign Relations Series, Experimental Edition, 1957 (Box 83, Folder 840)
  - An Exciting Profession: New Horizons for Secondary School Teachers, J. Lloyd Trump, undated (Box 83, Folder 841)
  - Looking at Modern Art, 1955 (Box 75, Folder 847)
    Text with reproduction prepared for discussion groups, sponsored by the Fund for Adult Education and the Art Institute of Chicago, Experimental Discussion Program
  - Assistants for Teachers of Exceptional Children, William M. Cruickshank and Norris G. Haring, 1957 (Box 75, Folder 848)
  - Classroom Revolution, by Terry Ferrer, Reprinted from the Herald Tribune (2 copies), 1963 (Box 83, Folder 842)
  - The Fact-Finding Study of the Testing Program of the United States Armed Forces Institute, Ralph W. Tyler, 1952-1954, 1954 July 1 (Box 83, Folder 843-845)